BHAGIRTHI JHAMB

WEB DEVELOPER

www.bjcodes.com

in linkedin.com/bhagirthijhamb

bhagirthi.jhamb@gmail.com

6

226 927 5011

<u>@BhagirthiJhamb</u>

github.com/bhagirthijhamb

PROFILE

I am a web developer, fully adapted to the Agile ways of working and passionate about building engaging, creative and intuitive web applications.

I have been developing web projects over 2 years now and I really enjoy crafting immersive experiences through code.

SKILLS

- HTML5
- CSS3/ Sass
- JavaScript/ES6
- React
- Redux
- MERN Stack
- Node.js
- Rest APIs
- Mongo DB
- Firebase
- Webpack
- Git/GitHub
- MySQL
- Unit Testing
- WCAG
- jQuery
- Bootstrap
- Responsive Web Design
- Pair Programming
- Communication

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Juno College of Technology

June 2019 - July 2020 | Web Developer

Technical Areas: | MERN Stack | React | Redux | NodeJS | MongoDB | Firebase | REST API

Role and Responsibilities:

- Mentor and code reviewer for Juno College Web Development Course.
- Help Students trouble shoot code bugs and issues with their projects.
- Closely collaborated with the Design Architect to understand design/implement it.
- Decomposing Design into User Stories
- Responsible for creating and submitting the wireframes.
- Integration with MongoDB/Firebase Database.

<u>Projects:</u>

<u>Exercise Tracker</u> | MERN Stack | REST APi | Bootstrap | Javascript | HTML5

Exercise Tracker is a full stack app that allows users to create profiles and create exercise logs.

- Used React library for front-end.
- Used NodeJS for creating RestAPI for the back-end
- Implemented CRUD operations for interacting with the API
- Used MongoDB as the database.

<u>Shopping List</u> | MERN Stack | Redux | ReactStrap | Javascript | HTML5

Its is a full stack app that allows users to create and update a simple shopping list.

- Used Redux as a state management tools for the application.
- ReactStrap is used as stylling the front-end
- NodeJS is used for creating the server and back-end
- MongoDB is used as the database of choice.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Create Party App | React | Router | Firebase | Rest API | Sass | HTML5 | Pair Programming

The App allows users to create guests with dietary restrictions and then create parties by searching recipes for selected guests.

- A corporate style React app built in collaboration with 3 other developers.
- Involved close collaboration with all module owners in development and integration phase of the project.
- Search recipes from Spoonacular API
- Firebase for storing user profiles and parties

Chat-Box | React | Firebase | JavaScript | Sass | HTML5

Chat-Box is a chat app that connects you with your friends in real time. It is built using REACT for front-end and Firebase for storage of groups, users and messages.

- User can create username, create/switch chat groups
- Send and delete messages

Larsen & Toubro Ltd.

Jan 2008 - Nov 2010 | Senior Engineer

Technical Areas: | jQuery | HTML | CSS | MS Office | AutoCAD

Role and Responsibilities:

- Developed an in-house HTML, CSS and jQuery based website for my department for the purpose of displaying progress.
- Responsible for deploying, maintaining and enhancing the website.
- Responsible for project monitoring, tracking progress and preparing progess reports for senior leadership review.
- Interacted with client for work and bill approval.

Hindustan Construction Company Ltd.

July 2006 - Jan 2008 | Project Engineer

Technical Areas: MS Project | AutoCAD | MS Excel | MS Word

Role and Responsibilities:

- Project Execution as per project specifications and methodology.
- Ensuring timely completion and keeping all stakeholders in sync.

EDUCATION:

Juno College Of Technology

- Web Development Immersive Bootcamp | Feb May 2020
- JavaScript Fundamentals | July Sep 2019
- Web Development Fundamentals | June 2019

University of California, Irvine

JavaScript Programming | July 2018

National Institute of Technology, Hamirpur, India

• B. Tech, Civil Engineering | June 2006